spinchat.com 2019-06-16

# Data protection regulation/privacy policy | Spinchat.com

(Last update: 24 May 2018)

Privacy Policy

Data protection is important to us. In the following we inform you about the collection of personal data when you visit our website and use the services offered here.

 **1\. Consent and revocation**

By registering with spinchat.com, the user consents to their personal data being collected, stored and processed in accordance with this data protection declaration and the GTC. The user must expressly declare this consent when creating the user profile.  
Consent to this privacy policy may be revoked at any time by the user by using the function provided by spinchat.com for complete deletion of the registration and user data.

After exercising your right of revocation, we will not process your personal data further, unless we can prove compelling grounds for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or if the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims.

 **2\. Access to spinchat.com via our website**

The following subitems apply when accessing our website by web browser.

 **2.1 Cookies**  
In order to make your visit to our website attractive and to enable the use of certain functions, we use so-called cookies on various pages. This serves to protect our overriding legitimate interests in an optimized presentation of our offer and to avoid multiple sign ins in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR.

Cookies are small text files that are automatically stored on your device. Some of the cookies we use are deleted after the end of the browser session, i.e. after closing your browser (so-called session cookies). Other cookies remain on your device and enable us to recognize your browser on your next visit (persistent cookies).

You can see the duration of storage in the overview in the cookie settings of your web browser. You can set your browser in such a way that you will be informed about the storage of cookies and decide individually about their acceptance or refuse the acceptance of cookies for certain cases or generally. Each browser differs in the way it manages the cookie settings. This is described in the help menu of each browser, which explains how you can change your cookie settings.

You can find them in our help document or, for different web browsers, under the following links:

Internet Explorer: https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies  
Safari: https://support.apple.com/kb/ph21411?locale=en_US  
Chrome: https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?hl=en&hlrm=en  
Firefox: https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences  
Opera: http://help.opera.com/Windows/10.20/en/cookies.html

If you do not accept cookies, the functionality of our website may be restricted.

 **2.2 Advertising placements**  
spinchat.com may use age, gender and city/state specified by the user to decide which advertisement should be displayed. The user has the possibility to deactivate this personalized advertising via the [prefs:]] on spinchat.com. In no case, however, will this data be passed on directly to other companies.

Further personal data of the user such as email address, telephone number, interests, location data and the like are not used by spinchat.com for advertising placements, however, advertising can be tailored to the text of the page on which it is displayed. spinchat.com generally does not send advertising e-mails or advertising SMS.

We use third parties to serve ads. These third party providers also learn the current IP address of the user without assignment to their personal data, and can store cookies in the userâs browser. These companies may use information (not including name, address, email address or telephone number) about the userâs visit to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about products and services of interest to the user.

Some of these third party providers are:

Google LLC

Our site uses Google AdSense to market space for third-party ads and advertising networks. These ads are displayed in various places on this website.  
This enables the display of interest-based advertising by automatically assigning a pseudonymous user ID, with the help of which the interests are determined on the basis of visits to this and other websites.  
After our use of Google AdSense has ended, the data collected in this context will be deleted.

Google AdSense is a service of Google LLC. (www.google.com)  
Google LLC is headquartered in the USA. There is a decree of appropriateness by the European Commission for this country. This goes back to the EU US Privacy Shield, under which Google LLC is certified. A current certificate can be viewed here: https://www.privacyshield.gov/list

Criteo SA - Germany - Privacy policy and opt-out possibility https://www.criteo.com/privacy/

Ad2Games GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: http://www.ad2games.com/privacy-policy/ Opt-out: http://ib.adnxs.com/optout  
Affilinet GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://www.affili.net/uk/footeritem/privacy-policy  
Amazon EU Sarl - Luxembourg - Privacy Policy: https://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=footer_privacy?ie=UTF8&nodeId=201909010 Opt-out: https://www.amazon.co.uk/adprefs  
arejo GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://www.adtiger.com/privacy/  
Awin AG - Germany - https://www.awin.com/gb/legal/privacy-policy  
Burgey Business Group GmbH (adiro.de) - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://www.adiro.de/kontakt/datenschutz  
Ceramex Media GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: http://www.ceramex-media.de/datenschutz.html  
Conversant Europe Ltd - UK - Privacy Policy: https://www.conversantmedia.com/legal/privacy Opt-out: http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/  
Cyberservices B.V. - The Netherlands - Privacy Policy: http://www.cyberservices.nl/en/datenschutz.php  
Jink GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: http://jink.de/datenschutz  
Ligatus GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://www.ligatus.com/en/privacy-policy  
MGA Intermedia GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://www.mga-intermedia.com/?p=datenschutz  
OpenX GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://www.openx.com/legal/privacy-policy/# Opt-out: https://www.openx.com/legal/interest-based-advertising/  
Performance Horizon Group Ltd - UK - Privacy Policy: https://performancehorizon.com/application/files/4414/8889/2534/phg_privacy.pdf  
Reachnet DE Ltd. - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://reachnet.de/unternehmen/datenschutz.html Opt-out: https://adfarm1.adition.com/opt?m=optout&n=73  
The Reach Group GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://www.reachgroup.com/en/privacy-statement Opt-out: https://www.reachgroup.com/en/opt-out/  
The Rubicon Project Ltd - UK - Privacy Policy: https://rubiconproject.com/privacy-policy/ Opt-out: https://rubiconproject.com/privacy/consumer-online-profile-and-opt-out/  
Ströer SSP GmbH (adscale.de) - Germany - Privacy Policy: http://www.adscale.de/datenschutz Opt-out: https://ih.adscale.de/adscale-ih/oo  
Yieldkit GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://yieldkit.com/legal-notes/privacy-policy/  
Yieldlove GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: https://www.yieldlove.com/cookie-policy  
Viversum GmbH - Germany - Privacy Policy: http://www.viversum.de/datenschutz

Further opt-out options for behavioural advertising can be found on the pages of the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance (EDAA)

 **2.3 Videos and graphics of external providers**  
Users have the possibility to embed videos and graphics of external providers on this website. By embedding such contents, the provider's servers are called due to technical reasons. For the use of data of your browser or deviceby using such a web page, we refer to the privacy policy of the respective providers. e.g. YouTube resp. Google or Vimeo.

 **3\. Access data**

You can visit our websites without providing any personal information.

Whenever users call individual pages, or log in or out, spinchat.com stores the current IP address, the name of the application used for access, as well as name and status of the requested file assigned to the pseudonym chosen by the user. Text publications in public chat rooms (not dialogs) are recorded.

These access data are evaluated in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR for the protection of our legitimate interests, which predominate within the scope of a weighing of interests, exclusively for the purpose of ensuring trouble-free operation of the site, optimizing our software and identifying and tracking inadmissible access attempts, for maintaining the terms of use and improving our offer. Under no circumstances will this data be used commercially or to create personality profiles.

The log files concerning website visits will, if no preliminary proceedings are pending, be deleted after 7 days; other log files such as the log-in/log-out or the public chat rooms log files will, if no preliminary proceedings are pending, be deleted no later than 3 months after their collection.

If dialog partners do not report abuse using the function provided in the dialog window, private dialogs are not saved permanently and cannot be viewed by spinchat.com employees. If one of the dialog participants reports an abuse via the function provided for this purpose in the dialog window, the last 30 minutes of this dialog are stored forgery-proof from the chat serverâs volatile main memory into the database as an abuse report.

Users also have the possibility to report abuse in other services in spinchat.com (e.g. dialogs/messages/profiles). Abuse reports are viewed by spinchat.com employees, checked and - if appropriate - forwarded to investigative authorities.

If the user buys optional offers (e.g. VIP or spin points), the corresponding payment data will be stored as long as necessary for processing the payment process; in the case of standing orders, until the user stops the standing order or deletes his registered account.

 **4\. Correction and deletion of data**

The user has the possibility to change their entered data at any time, with the exception of the telephone number they might have entered for the registration process, their gender and date of birth. If you want to change the gender or date of birth in your profile, please contact our customer service.

Consent to this privacy policy can be revoked by the user using the function provided by spinchat.com for complete Deletion of their registration and their data.

Profile details and photos will be completely removed upon deletion. Content posted by the user in public areas, e.g. forum posts, will remain - without the personal data from the profile. Messages sent to other users, such as dialogs, e-mails, guestbook entries or gifts, are retained by these users. Public contributions in which the user has inadvertently disclosed sensitive/personal data can, however, be subsequently removed by contacting our customer service stating the URL to be removed exactly.

The data of users who are banned and blocked by SPiN AG will be retained within a 30-day period during which such a block can still be reversed if it is based on an error. After expiry of this period, the user's profile details and photos will be automatically deleted as after a self-initiated deletion; however, we reserve the right, in accordance with Art. 6 (1) point f GDPR, to protect our legitimate interests, which predominate in the context of a weighing of interests, to store data which are necessary to maintain the block itself, such as the pseudonym, email address and telephone number used for registration beyond this period, whereby this data will under no circumstances be used in any other way than to maintain the ban.

 **5\. Transmission of data**

Depending on which payment service provider you select in the order process, we pass on the payment data collected for the processing of payments to the credit institution commissioned with the payment and, if applicable, to payment service providers commissioned by us or to the selected payment service. In some cases, the selected payment service providers also collect this data themselves if you create an account there. In this case, you must log in to the payment service provider with your access data during the ordering process. The data protection declaration of the respective payment service provider applies in this respect.

 **6\. Possibilities to contact us and your rights**

As a person concerned, you have the following rights:

in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR the right to request information about your personal data processed by us to the extent described therein;  
in accordance with Art. 16 GDPR the right to demand immediately the correction of incorrect or complete personal data stored by us;  
in accordance with Art. 17 GDPR, the right to request the deletion of your personal data stored by us unless further processing is necessary  
\- to exercise freedom of expression and information;  
\- for fulfilment of a legal obligation;  
\- on grounds of public interest or  
\- for asserting, exercising or defending legal claims  
in accordance with Art. 18 of the GDPR, the right to request that the processing of your personal data be restricted insofar as  
\- the correctness of the data is denied by you;  
\- the processing is unlawful, but you refuse deletion;  
\- we no longer need the data, but you do need it to assert, exercise or defend legal claims, or  
\- you have lodged an objection to the processing pursuant to Art. 21 GDPR;  
in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR the right to receive your personal data that you have made available to us in a structured, common and machine-readable format or to request its transfer to another person in charge;  
In accordance with Art. 77 GDPR the right to complain to a supervisory authority. As a rule, you can contact the supervisory authority at your usual place of residence or workplace or at our company headquarters.

If you have any questions regarding the collection, processing or use of your personal data, information, correction, blocking or deletion of data or revocation of consent given or objection to a specific use of data, please contact us directly via the contact data in our imprint.

 **7\. Right of revocation**

If we process personal data as described above in order to protect our legitimate interests, which predominate within the scope of a weighing of interests, you can object to this processing with effect for the future.  
After exercising your right of revocation, we will not process your personal data further for these purposes, unless we can prove compelling reasons worthy of protection for the processing, which outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or if the processing serves to assert, exercise or defend legal claims.

 **8\. Changes to the Privacy Policy**

spinchat.com reserves the right to amend this privacy policy and to adapt it to current legal practice within the framework of applicable laws. Users will be informed about this at a suitable place, e.g. the start page, the announcement area or directly upon login.

 **9\. Party responsible and contact person for data protection**

Party responsible according to Art. 4 (7) GDPR is SPiN AG (see our imprint). Our data protection officer Sonja Tietz can be contacted via email to [datenschutz@spin-ag.de](mailto:datenschutz@spin-ag.de) or via letter to the address given in our imprint.
